Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Engravings by Richard Shirley Smith, Series IV
  - Nude in Garden, 1960; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4 x 7.7 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [2])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "Juvenillia R.S.S. Rome 1960."
  - Mother and Child, circa 1960; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7 x 4.5 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [3])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "Richard Shirley Smith."
  - 13 Southwood Mansions, 1962; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 2.3 x 5.2 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [4])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "Richard Shirley Smith '62."
  - NIGEL FINZI Artist's Proof, 1963; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 1.5 x 6.3 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [5])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "A.P. Richard Shirley Smith. '63."
    Wood engravings; Finzi, Nigel, 1936-2010
  - Portrait of James Henry Newman for Newman Companion to the Gospels, 1966; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.3 x 3.7 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [6])
    Wood engravings; Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890
  - Italian Townscape rejected design for Poems of Shelley, circa 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 6.5 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [7])
    Not in Bain. No inscription.
  - Wellhead rejected design for Poems of Shelley, circa 1970; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 6.5 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [8])
    Not in Bain. Inscribed in graphite: "AP Richard Shirley Smith."
    Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Poems; Wells; Wood engravings
  - Nymph and Pulcinella Study for no. 238, 1976; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 4.5 x 5.5 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [9])
  - Pair of nudes bracketing chapter head, undated; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 7.5 x 23 cm (Box 18, Folder not in Bain [10])
  - Lattice window open in moonlight, for Poems of Shelley, 1971; Shirley Smith, Richard; [4] pages; 10 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder K)
    Page [1] features Shirley Smith's engraving (Bain no. 201); page [3] comprises four lines of verse by Joy Finzi. In purple wrappers, with the engraving repeated on the front cover.
  - Design used for dust jacket of Richard Shirley Smith: Illustrated Books, Engravings and Bookplates: Annotated Checklist, Roger W. Moss Collection, 2009; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 30 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder add. 3)
  - Untitled (Green Man), 1960; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 16 x 30 cm (Box 3, Folder add. 4)
  - Miranda, 2002; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 50 x 36 cm (Box Folio 1, Folder Fol. add. 1-2)
    Depicts a portion of the image from Shirley Smith's painting: Miranda at Didyma. Signed and dated in ink.
    Two copies are present, one on blue-green paper and a second on white paper.
  - Design for patterned endpapers of The Highgrove Florilegium, 2008; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 62 x 31 cm, folded to 31 x 31 cm (Box Folio 1, Folder Fol. add. 3)
    Richard Shirley Smith's vignettes of features from the Highgrove garden were used as endpapers and throughout the text of The Highgrove florilegium (2008).
  - Baroque wreck, 1969; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: linocut; 36 x 52 cm (Box Folio 1, Folder Fol. add. 4)
    Signed, in graphite: "1/100. Baroque Wreck. Lino engraving. Richard Shirley Smith. 1969."
  - Roma, 2006; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 print: wood engraving; 26 x 31 cm (Box Folio 1, Folder Fol. add. 5)
    Signed in graphite: "125/200. Engraved Roma 1961, revised & printed 2006, Richard Shirley Smith."
- Ephemera, Series V
  - Leslie Hyam & R.S.S. at Harrow, circa 1950; 1 sheet; 15.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Photocopy of a black and white photograph.
    Photocopies; Shirley Smith, Richard; Hyam, Leslie A.
  - Title leaf: Prospect: the Schweppes book of the new generation advisory editor Roger Bannister. Hutchinson of London., 1962; 1 sheet; 23 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Item comprises title leaf only.
  - Printed cover: Mervyn Burtch, When April Came. London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1962., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 25.5 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Dust jacket illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Moss no. 39.
  - Aspects of Rome. From: Prospect: The Schweppes Book of the New Generation. London: Hutchinson, 1962., Shirley Smith, Richard; 6 pages; 23 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 3a)
    Comprises the six pages of Prospect (Moss no. 1) concerning Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Printed cover: Olive Rees, Toy Cupboard Songs. London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1963., Rees, Olive; 1 sheet; 23.5 x 15.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Dust jacket illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Moss no. 4.
  - Dust jacket: F.M. Dostoevsky, Memoires from the House of the Dead., 1965; Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, 1821-1881; 1 folded sheet; 15 x 22 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Dust jacket illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Composers' Guild of Great Britain. Ralph Vaughan Williams Award Composer of the year. 1964. Benjamin Britten, President, Chairman. June 13 1965., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 31 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    With a wood-engraved illustration of Ralph Vaughan Williams by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Wood engravings; Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958; Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976
  - Dust jacket: Masters of Music: Britten. Percy M. Young, 1966; Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; 1 folded sheet; 22 x 29.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Dust jackets; Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976
  - Dust jacket: The Heart of Thomas More. Selected Readings for Every Day Arranged by E.E. Reynolds, 1966; Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894-; 1 folded sheet; 16.5 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Dust jacket engraving by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Dust jacket: Masters of Music: Stravinsky. Percy M. Young, 1969; Young, Percy M. (Percy Marshall), 1912-2004; 1 folded sheet; 22.5 x 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Dust jackets; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
  - Dust jacket: Masters of Music: Haydn. Percy M. Young, 1969; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 22 x 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition announcement: 29 June - 16 July. Richard Shirley Smith. Waterhouse Gallery. Collages, paintings, engravings., 1971; 1 sheet; 22 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Waterhouse Gallery (London, England)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith Collages. November 6th to 26th. Waterhouse Gallery., 1973; 1 folded sheet; 10 x 28.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Paintings and Collages. Oxford Gallery. January 12 to February 11, 1976., 1 sheet; 16 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Oxford Gallery (Oxford, England)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Two Exhibitions. Collingwood College and University Library, Durham., 1976; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 21 x 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Bain no. 238.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Collingwood College; Durham University Library
  - Exhibition announcement: Figurative Painting. Borough of Thamesdown Museum and Art Gallery. 4th-26th June 1977., 1 sheet; 10 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Invitation: Mr. and Mrs. Lionel Conway. Mural decoration & preparatory studies by Richard Shirley Smith., 1978; 1 sheet; 14 x 18.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    With wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Two copies.
    Invitations; Wood engravings; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Invitation: Richard Shirley Smith. Montages and engravings. 20 February to 15 March 1978. Oxford Gallery, 23 High Street, Oxford., 1 sheet; 20.5 x 14.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Bain no. 194.
    Invitations; Shirley Smith, Richard; Oxford Gallery (Oxford, England)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Engravings & montages. Oxford Gallery, 23 High Street, Oxford. 20 February to 15 March 1978., 1 sheet; 18 x 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 17a)
    With a wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith
    Advertisements; Wood engravings; Shirley Smith, Richard; Oxford Gallery (Oxford, England)
  - Business card: Phrogg. Peter Drew, Harrogate design firm., 1980; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 8 x 5 cm (Box 1, Folder 18)
    With wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Trade cards (advertising); Wood engravings; Drew, Peter, active 1980; Phrogg (Harrogate, England)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith, paintings and prints., 1980; 1 folded sheet; 20.5 x 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Wood engravings, montages & paintings. 31 March to 21 April 1980. Private view Sunday 30 March. David & Sue Potter, The Studio, Kings Arms Yard, Dorchester, Dorset., 1 sheet; 12.6 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Bain no. 169.
  - Exhibition announcement: Engraver & Printer, Michael Mitchell and Richard Shirley Smith. Blewbury Festival. 16 and 17 June 2pm to 6pm., 1981; 1 sheet; 21 x 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-
  - Eric Gill. The visitation: a wood engraving., 1981; 1 folded sheet; 18 x 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 21a)
    Published by David & Sue Potter, in an edition of 250 copies. This copy is unnumbered and lacks the engraving (consists of the paper folder only).
    Gill, Eric, 1882-1940
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Studies for mural decorations & wood engravings. Sunday 17 October to 20 November 1982. Katharine House Gallery, Marlborough., 1 sheet; 21 x 9.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Bain no. 180.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Katharine House Gallery (Marlborough, England)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Montages, studies for mural decorations, paintings & wood engravings. Saturday 27 November to 19 December 1982. Borlase Gallery, South Street, Blewbury., 1 sheet; 9.6 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Bain no. 183.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Borlase Gallery (Blewbury, England)
  - Return address: ISB from Iain Bain., 1983; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 10.8 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 24)
    With illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Bain no. 253.
    Wood engravings; Bain, Iain
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith Retrospective Exhibition 1985. Ashmolean Museum, Oxford. 4 September to 3 November., 1983; 1 sheet; 11 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Ashmolean Museum
  - Program: Metamorphoses. Opera cycle in five parts by Richard Blackford. The Royal College of Music Opera School, Centenary Production., 1983; Shirley Smith, Richard; 4 pages; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Cover illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Theater programs; Blackford, Richard, 1954-; Royal College of Music (Great Britain)
  - Invitation: New pictures & wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith. Ceramics by Anna Lambert, Kathryn Lawrence, Sasha Wardell. Sunday 29 May to 1 July 1983. Katharine House Gallery, the Parade, Marlborough, Wiltshire., 1 sheet; 10 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Invitations; Wardell, Sasha; Shirley Smith, Richard; Lambert, Anna; Lawrence, Kathryn; Katharine House Gallery (Marlborough, England)
  - Advertisement: The Sapient Pig 29 Oxford Street, Newbury., 1984; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 9.8 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 28)
    With a wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Bain no. 74.
    Advertisements; Wood engravings; Restaurants -- Great Britain
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith Retrospective Exhibition. Ashmolean Museum, Oxford. 4 September to 3 November. Riba Heinz Gallery, 21 Portman Square, London. 14 November to 21 December., 1985; 1 sheet; 23 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Seven copies.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Ashmolean Museum; Heinz Gallery
  - Title label: Messer Pietro Mio. The Engravings. Richard Shirley Smith., 1985; 1 sheet; 3 x 8.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Spine label applied to cloth clamshell box of Moss no. 112.
    Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Cantate Dno Caticum Novum, circa 1985; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 17 x 11 cm (Box 1, Folder 31)
    With wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith. Bain no. 281.
  - Exhibition leaflet: Richard Shirley Smith, wood engravings, montages & paintings. 16th February-7th March, Sewell Centre, Radley College., circa 1985?; 4 pages; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 31a)
    Includes a price list of works exhibited. Reproduces several wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Selected Pictures in the Old Speech Room Gallery, Harrow School, 1986; 24 pages; 21 x 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 32)
    "Richard Shirley Smith [b 1935]: Archaeological Fragments, 1986"--pages 22-23. "Richard Shirley Smith [b 1935]: Still-Life on dish with George I Medal, 1989"--page 24.
    Shirley Smith, Richard; Harrow School. Old Speech Room Gallery
  - Prospectus: Symposium of Plato. Translated by Tom Griffith. Engraved by Peter Forster. Libanus Press. December 1986., Griffith, Tom; 2 sheets; 27.5 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Libanus Press
  - Exhibition announcement: Wood Engravings and Mural Cartoons. Richard Shirley Smith. Gallery 44, Forty-First Aldeburgh Festival. 44 High Street, Aldeburgh, Suffolk. 10 to 26 June 1988., 1 sheet; 11.5 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts
  - Note card with architectural engraving, circa 1989; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 15.5 x 10.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Program: A Farewell Tribute. Joy Finzi. St. Martin's Church, East Woodhay. 14 September 1991., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 22 x 14.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 36)
    With a wood-engraved illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Wood engravings; Programs; Finzi, Joy, 1907-1991
  - Advertisement: 3a Palace Green, Kensington Palace Gardens. Book of interior designs., 1991?; Regalian Properties (London, England); 16 pages; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 36a)
    "This book presents the work of the five world renowned interior designers who have been retained by Regalian Properties Plc to provide finished interiors for purchasers of apartments in 3a Palace Green, Kensington Palace Gardens, London."--Page 1.
    The front cover reproduces four murals by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Advertisements; Interior decoration -- Great Britain; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Exhibition announcement: Pictures for Books, an exhibition of wood engraved book illustration by Richard Shirley Smith and Simon Brett at Katharine House, The Parade, Marlborough, Wilts. 13 June - 4 July., 1992; 1 sheet; 10 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Advertisements; Wood-engraving -- Great Britain; Shirley Smith, Richard; Brett, Simon, 1943-; Katharine House Gallery (Marlborough, England)
  - Festival brochure: Marlborough Festival of Music and the Arts. 12 June - 5 July 1992., 1 folded sheet; 21 x 10 cm (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Brochures; Wood engravings; Shirley Smith, Richard; Marlborough Festival of Music and the Arts
  - Exhibition announcement: Recent Work, Richard Shirley Smith. Maas Gallery, 15a Clifford Street, London. 12 to 24 May 1992., 1 folded sheet; 21.5 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Two copies.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Maas Gallery (London, England)
  - Brochure: 300 Years of the Devonshire Dukedom., 1994; 12 pages; 21 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 40)
    With crest illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Brochures; Cavendish family; Devonshire, Dukes of
  - Festival brochure: Open Studios. Marlborough Festival '96. 11 to 6 on Weekends July 13th to 28th., 1995; 1 folded sheet; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Brochures; Shirley Smith, Richard; Marlborough Festival of Music and the Arts
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Maas Gallery 7-24 November 1995., 1 folded sheet; 16 x 21.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Holburne Museum. 13 February to 9 April, 1996., 1 sheet; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Holburne Museum and Crafts Study Centre
  - Dust jacket: Forbidden Fruit. La Fontaine., 1998; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 20.5 x 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Illustration by Richard Shirley Smith.
  - Invitation: Richard Shirley Smith paintings, drawings and wood engravings. Chris Beetles Limited 1999., 1 sheet; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Invitations; Shirley Smith, Richard; Chris Beetles Limited
  - Bookplates: Ex Libris Lord Butler of Brockwell and Ex Libris P&D Colnaghi, 2000; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 sheets; 43 x 29.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Enlarged photocopy of engraving with smaller bookplate engraving folded inside.
    Bookplates; Wood engravings; P. & D. Colnaghi & Co.; Butler of Brockwell, Frederick Edward Robin Butler, Baron, 1938-
  - Keepsake: AD 1950-2000. A Double Celebration for the 80th Birthdays of the Duke and Duchess of Devonshire and the 50th Anniversary of the Duke Becoming Head of the Cavendish Family. 14 & 15 July 2000, Chatsworth., Shirley Smith, Richard; 20 pages; 24 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Cover logo by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Keepsakes; Devonshire, Andrew Robert Buxton Cavendish, Duke of, 1920-2004; Devonshire, Deborah Vivien Freeman-Mitford Cavendish, Duchess of, 1920-2014
  - Invitation: Open Studio, Studio House, Sunday, 21 July 2002., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Invitations; Studio House (Firm)
  - Invitation: Richard Shirley Smith. The Paintings & Collages 1957-2000. Exhibition Dates 3-13 April. Chris Beetles Ltd., 2002; 1 sheet; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 48b)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith, designs for books 1960-2002. Engravings, bindings, illustrations, linocuts, montages & bookplates. Marlborough College, the Mount House Gallery., 1 sheet; 22.5 x 14.3 cm (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Marlborough College (Marlborough, England). Mount House Gallery
  - Invitation (drawing): Open Studio, Studio House, Elcot Lane, Marlborough, circa 2002?; Studio House (Firm); 1 sheet; 21 x 30 cm (Box 1, Folder 49a)
    Photocopied invitation to an open house at Studio House. The page is comprised almost entirely of a drawing by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Invitations; Pen and ink drawings; Studio House (Firm)
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Paintings, engravings, designs for books & cartoons for mural decorations. Harrow School, Old Speech Room Gallery. Exhibition dates: 14 February - 5 May 2003., 1 sheet; 30 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Harrow School. Old Speech Room Gallery
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith. Paintings, engravings, designs for books & cartoons for mural decorations. Harrow School, Old Speech Room Gallery. Private View. Thursday 13 February 2003., 1 sheet; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Two copies. Bain no. 240.
  - Photographs of Cycle of Life (mural), 2004; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 photographs; 13 x 20 cm (Box 1, Folder 51a)
  - Invitation: Richard Shirley Smith's 70th birthday. 29 July 2005., 1 folded sheet; 15 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 52)
    The reception to be held at The Kindersley Centre on the Lambourn Downs.
    Front panel with illustration by Shirley Smith.
    Invitations; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Invitation: Sir Roy Strong's 70th birthday lunch. 27th August 2005., 1 sheet; 15.5 x 22.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Invitations; Strong, Roy
  - Menu card: RS, 23 August 1935, Still Here. Tuesday 12 July 2005., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 54)
    "Designs for invitations and menu cards by Richard Shirley Smith. Printed at Libanus Press, Marlborough."--Back panel.
    Invitations; Menus; Strong, Roy
  - Postcard: Sir Roy Strong, the Laskett., 2006; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 10.5 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Postcards; Strong, Roy
  - Albin Brunovsky Certificate of Honour awarded to Richard Shirley Smith for outstanding contributions to bookplate design. FISAE, International Federation of Ex Libris Societies. 31 July 2007., International Federation of Ex-libris Societies; 1 sheet; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Certificates; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Invitation: Private view of Richard Shirley Smith: skill, imagination, versatility. Paintings, collages, engravings and designs for murals and books. Wiltshire Heritage Museum, Devizes., 2008; 1 sheet; 9.5 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Invitations; Shirley Smith, Richard; Wiltshire Heritage Museum
  - Lynda Franklin Antiques & Interiors. Business cards and postcards designed by Richard Shirley Smith., 2008; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 sheet; 8.5 x 5.5 and 10.5 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Two business cards and three postcards.
    Trade cards (advertising); Postcards; Franklin, Lynda
  - Exhibition announcement: Richard Shirley Smith: Skill, Imagination, Versatility. Paintings, collages, engravings and designs for murals and books. 5 April to 15 June 2008. Wiltshire Heritage Museum., 2 folded sheets; 21 x 15 cm (Box 1, Folder 59)
    With wood-engraved illustrations by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Advertisements; Shirley Smith, Richard; Wiltshire Heritage Museum
  - Invitation: Reception for Sir Roy Strong. 14 December 2009, Divinity School, Old Schools Quadrangle, Bodleian Library., Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 10 x 21 cm (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Two copies. Cover drawings by Richard Shirley Smith.
    Invitations; Strong, Roy; Bodleian Library
  - Prospectus: The High Grove Florilegium. Published for the Prince's Charities Foundation by Addison Publications Ltd., 2009 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Photographs of murals and wood engravings by Richard Shirley Smith, 2009; Shirley Smith, Richard; 6 photographs; 13 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - "The tower of boxes" (from a Persian folk tale), 1960s?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 4 sheets; 21 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 63)
    A children's story about a king who attempts to reach the moon by way of a tower of boxes. Written in pen and black ink, in the hand of Shirley Smith (and with his ink stamp at the head of the first leaf).
  - "The tower of boxes": slides of collages., 1960s?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 15 35mm slides (Box 1, Folder 64)
    35mm slides of mixed media collages to illustrate the story of "The tower of boxes." The slides are numbered in pen and black ink. Several are also inscribed with the title, and two are inscribed "Dennis Dobson pbr." Shirley Smith illustrated several works published by Dobson in the mid-1960s, but there is no evidence that "The tower of boxes" was ever published.
    Collages; Transparencies -- Color
  - Arcadian Bembo, circa 2000?; Tru Typographic Research Unit Ltd.; [16] pages; 32 x 24 cm (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Type specimen book for Arcadian Bembo, Roman, Italic, and Expert typefaces, developed by Tru Typographic Research Unit Limited in association with Monotype Imaging Ltd.. Page 3 includes a reproduction (at a reduced scale) of Richard Shirley Smith's engraving of Pietro Bembo.
    Type specimens; Tru Typographic Research Unit Ltd.; Monotype Imaging Ltd.
  - Instructions on the proper mounting of wood engravings, 2000s?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 folded sheet; 21 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Manuscript note, in the hand of Richard Shirley Smith (to Roger W. Moss?) on how to mount prints with sufficient space in the margins. Accompanied a batch of prints: "There are 13 prints, some numbered & limited, some artist's proofs. Some are the last I have & some are much finer than others ..."